# Nai Saevang

(828) 302-5081 | naisaevng@gmail.com | www.naisaevang.netlify.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Goal-oriented full stack software engineer with strong commitment to collaboration and solutions-oriented problem-solving. Experience building and maintaining consumer facing websites and software applications. Committed to high standards of user experience, usability and speed for end-users.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Freelance Web Developer, Remote - Full Stack Developer

APRIL 2018 - PRESENT

- Built and managed multiple Shopify ecommerce stores.
- Customized themes and fixed front end templates in HTML, Liquid, SASS, and JavaScript.

## **SeedSpark, Charlotte** - Software Applications Developer

JANUARY 2015 - APRIL 2018

- Responsible for creating a custom content management system from scratch in PHP and MySQL that powered most of our client consumer-facing websites that increased web traffic by up to 100%. It was built with the Laravel MVC framework.
- Analyzed requirements and designs, developed and implemented software applications for multiple websites using ASP.NET and SQL Server.
- Maintained existing applications, handled tickets from clients, and delivered new features using agile methodologies.

# RECENT PROJECTS

#### Alfred - github.com/naizen/alfred

- A real-time chatbot assistant that incorporates natural language processing to handle responses to the user.
- **Live Demo:** https://alfred-chatbot.netlify.com/
- Stack: React, Pusher ChatKit, Wit.ai

## **Movie Library** - github.com/naizen/movielibrary

- A web application where you can explore movies in theaters, popular, and upcoming. You can also search and view detailed movie info.
- **Live Demo:** https://movielibraryapp.netlify.com/
- Stack: React, Apollo GraphQL, TMDB API

FoodMatcher- <a href="mailto:github.com/naizen/foodmatcher">github.com/naizen/foodmatcher</a>

- An application that helps you figure out where you want to eat by matching you with food places nearby.
- **Live Demo:** <a href="https://foodmatcher.netlify.com/">https://foodmatcher.netlify.com/</a>
- Stack: React, Redux, Yelp API

# **Taskboard** - github.com/naizen/taskboard

- A Trello-inspired list application that allows users to add, remove, search, label, and reorganize lists and cards.
- **Live Demo:** <a href="https://taskboard-app.netlify.com/">https://taskboard-app.netlify.com/</a>
- Stack: Node, Express, MongoDB, React, Redux

# **EDUCATION**

**University of North Carolina at Charlotte** - Bachelor of Science: Computer Science AUGUST 2010 - MAY 2014

## **SKILLS & LANGUAGES**

Front End: Javascript, jQuery, React/Redux, HTML/CSS/SASS

Back End: PHP, MySQL, Laravel, WordPress, Shopify, ASP.NET, VB, C#, SQL

Server, Node, Express, RESTful APIs, Apollo GraphQL